Oliver J. Daubney

MChem PhD AMRSC

oliver.j.daubney@gmail.com • +44(0)7909333237 • Oxfordshire

GitHub - www.github.com/OliverDaubney/data analysis portfolio

Personal Statement:

Dedicated and fast learning analyst with over 8 years of experience in analytics and data-led problem solving. Background including a master's degree and doctoral degree in Chemistry, as well as the Google professional data analytics course. Recently, overhauled an entire web services UI and look forward to using my design and analysis skills to create insightful visualisations and build efficient frameworks for data storage as an operations analyst.

Skills and Expertise:

Data Analysis – Collection, cleaning, validating, managing and visualising data such as time-series harmonic data and large multidimensional arrays for crystallography.

Software Proficiencies - Python, SQL, Spreadsheets, R, Tableau, PHP, HTML and CSS.

Version Control – Git and GitHub.

Communication – Report preparation and discussion with clients and stakeholders to demonstrate progress and construct plans of action.

Problem Solving – Strong analytical skills demonstrated by reducing building energy consumption by >70% for a charitable organisation following critical analysis of their energy usage.

Project Management – Supervised and managed internal stakeholders as well as outsourced consultants for project delivery. Involved in training junior team members.

Teamwork – Enjoyed working in interdisciplinary teams both in academia to publish novel science and in recent technology developments to deliver well tested products.

Employment History:

Chief Technology Officer – *Utilivista Ltd.* (*October 2022 – present*). Developing data analysis pipelines alongside UI redesign, IoT technology testing and operational improvement. Key experience communicating effectively with both stakeholders and clients whilst managing teams to deliver results. Consultant – *Research and Development Consultants Ltd.* (*January 2019 – present*). Involved collecting, analysing, and presenting data to assist with problem solving. An example included collecting signal propagation data to create and deploy an optimised MESH network. Experience writing and presenting summary reports for companies, plans of action and proposals for new work/funding.

University of Birmingham, School of Chemistry;

- **Teaching Associate Equipment Training** (September 2015 September 2018): Providing training for PhD and MSci students on a range of experimental equipment.
- Teaching Associate Postgraduate Demonstrating (January 2016 September 2018): Supervising students during their practical lessons, ensuring safe conditions and marking their performance.

Systems Analyst - *Utilivista Ltd.* (*July 2011 – September 2016*). Analysing and problem solving for IoT hardware packages to integrate with a remote access server system.

Education:

Data Analytics Professional Certificate (Coursera - Google; *June 2023 – September 2023*): To showcase and consolidate my knowledge in data analysis.

PhD Chemistry (University of Birmingham; *September 2015 – January 2019*): A Biomimetic Approach for Light Harvesting using Lanthanide Binding Coiled Coils. In the group of Dr. A. Peacock (UoB), supervised by Dr. L. Cox (UoB) and Prof. G. Worth (UCL).

Oliver J. Daubney

MChem PhD AMRSC

oliver.j.daubney@gmail.com • +44(0)7909333237 • Oxfordshire

Undergraduate Chemistry Degree (MChem) (University of York; September 2011 – July 2015): Master in Chemistry, First-Class Honours. Research project in the group of Prof. D. Smith.

A Levels (Caistor Grammar School; *September 2009 – June 2011*): Chemistry (A), Mathematics (A), Physics (B), General Studies (B) and an AS Level in Further Mathematics (B).

GCSE's (Caistor Grammar School; *September 2004 – July 2009*): Mathematics (A), Statistics (A), Physics (A), Chemistry (A*), Biology (A), Eng. Language (A), Eng. Literature (A), History (A), Design and Technology (A), Music (A) and French (B).

Selected Publications, Conferences and Awards:

Publication - Taylor, M. P., Daubney, O. J., Soto, C. and Worth, G. A. (2024), Rapid Emission Prediction of Small Polyaromatic Hydrocarbons. Manuscript in progress and available upon request. **Publication -** Slope, L. N., Daubney, O. J., Campbell, H., White, S. A. and Peacock A. F. A. (2021), Location-Dependent Lanthanide Selectivity Engineered into Structurally Characterized Designed Coiled Coils. *Angew. Chem. Int. Ed.*, **60**, 24473-24477.

Oral Presentation - Dalton 2018 - University of Warwick, 3rd-5th April 2018.

Oral Presentation - 1st Bristol BioDesign Institute Conference (Presentation) – University of Bristol, 10th May 2018

Award - 14th International Symposium on Applied Bioinorganic Chemistry (ISABC) (BACHEM Poster Award) – Toulouse, France, 7th June -10th June 2017.

Publication - Jamshad, M., Chandler, R., Jeeves, M., Robinson, A., Alam, F., Cranford-Smith, T., Shah, A., Daubney, O., Dunne, K., Nabi, N., Iqbal, A., Peacock, A., Lovett, J., Knowles, T., Henderson, I. and Huber, D. (2017), A genetic screen suggests an alternative mechanism for inhibition of SecA by azide. *bioRxiv*.

Publication - Cornwell, D. J., Daubney, O. J. and Smith, D. K. (2015), Photopatterned Multidomain Gels: Multi-Component Self-Assembled Hydrogels Based on Partially Self-Sorting 1,3:2,4-Dibenzylidene-D-sorbitol Derivatives. *J. Am. Chem. Soc.*, 2015, **137**(49), 15486-15492.